Hello, everyone. So welcome to the 18th lecture of CS162 2021. So today we are going to talk
大家好。欢迎来到2021年CS162第18讲。今天我们将讨论的内容是
about general input output. And just to summarize, so far we have studied abstractions, the API
关于通用输入输出。总结一下，到目前为止，我们已经学习了抽象和应用程序接口（API）。
which is provided by the operating system to the application to run a process. We talk
操作系统为应用程序提供的用于运行进程的接口。我们谈论的是
quite a bit about the virtual memory, demand paging, how to manage the physical memory,
关于虚拟内存、需求分页和如何管理物理内存，有相当多的知识。
and about virtualization. And we also talk about synchronization and scheduling. Okay?
关于虚拟化。我们还要谈论同步和调度。好吗？
So and how to manage the CPU resources and how to synchronize to have multiple processes
如何管理CPU资源以及如何同步多个进程呢？
and multiple threads, accessing the same resources and how they can cooperate in order to implement
和多个线程，访问相同的资源以及它们如何合作以实现
some more complex functionality. Okay? So now one thing we haven't talked as much so far is about
一些更复杂的功能。好吗？到目前为止，我们还没有谈论过的一件事是关于什么？
input and output. And obviously the input output is a fundamental part of any computer system,
输入和输出。显然，输入输出是任何计算机系统的基本组成部分。
because that's why how we interact with the computers through some input output devices
因为这就是我们通过一些输入输出设备与计算机进行交互的方式。
like keyboards, mouse, cameras, and things like that. And also this is how the computer itself
喜欢键盘、鼠标、相机之类的东西。还有，这就是计算机本身。
interact with the environment and with us, displaying information on the screen,
与环境和我们进行互动，将信息显示在屏幕上，
printing information, and other things like that. Right? Now the biggest problem, and this is
打印信息，还有其他类似的东西。对吗？现在最大的问题是，这是
what also makes this also this lecture a little bit maybe harder, is that
还有一个让这个讲座可能会更难一点的原因是，
it's there are a huge variety of this input output devices.
这里有各种各样的输入输出设备。
Right? Actually, if you think about others, like memory, memory is pretty simple. It's an array
对吗？实际上，如果你考虑其他的东西，比如内存，内存是相当简单的。它是一个数组。
of addressable bytes. Right? That's pretty much what it is. If you think about the CPUs and so
可寻址字节的数量。对吗？基本上就是这样。如果你考虑一下CPU和其他的东西。
forth, from our perspective, it's a resource which we want to probably time slice in time,
从我们的角度来看，这是一个我们可能想要在时间上进行分配的资源。
time slice, so then we can visualize it. So we created this illusion that every process has
时间片，这样我们就可以将其可视化。因此，我们创造了这种错觉，即每个进程都有
access to its own machine, virtual machine. Right? But if you look about input output
访问自己的机器，虚拟机。对吗？但是如果你考虑输入输出的话。
devices, this is a huge variety. And not only in terms of the sizes, not only in terms of the speed
设备，这是一个巨大的种类。不仅仅是在尺寸上，也不仅仅是在速度上。
they operate at, you can have networking, which is hundreds of gigabytes per second versus keyboard,
他们的运行速度可以达到每秒数百千兆字节，而键盘只是几千字节。
which is one character per whatever second. But also in terms of reliability, in some cases,
每秒钟一个字符。但在可靠性方面，在某些情况下，
you can lose information like packets on the network can be lost. So you need to recover.
你可以丢失信息，就像网络上的数据包可能会丢失一样。所以你需要进行恢复。
So in all aspects in low dimension, you have a huge variety. And yet the operating system
所以在低维度的所有方面，你有很多选择。然而操作系统
needs to cope with this variety in a reasonable way. Right? You don't want to be exposed.
需要以合理的方式应对这种多样性。对吗？你不想被暴露出来。
And what that means, you don't want your program, when you are developing your program, to think
而这意味着，你不希望在开发程序时，你的程序会去思考。
about each of these input devices in a different way. Right? And this is the role of the operating
是的，对每个输入设备以不同的方式进行介绍。这就是操作系统的作用。
system. Again, despite this huge variety to provide us with an interface, which is reasonable,
系统。尽管有如此多的选择来为我们提供一个合理的界面，但是再次强调，
which is reasonable, you know, scoped, and you can make sense of it. And you don't need to,
哪个是合理的，你知道的，有限的，并且你可以理解它。而且你不需要，
you know, think about different concepts or you are going to operate on different IOD devices.
你知道，考虑不同的概念或者你将要操作不同的IOD设备。
Okay. And this is a, if you remember, this is a figure we have shown a few times in the past.
好的。如果你还记得的话，这是一个我们过去几次展示过的图表。
And here this protection boundary switches down here, it's also abstracts away
这个保护边界在这里切换，它也抽象了起来。
this input output devices.
这是输入输出设备。
Okay. So today we are going to talk about how you are going to get the impact, you know,
好的。所以今天我们要谈谈你如何获得影响力，你知道的，
how you are going to get this kind of input from these devices. And eventually,
你将如何从这些设备中获取这种输入。最终，
where do you need to get this input? This input from these devices, you need to put in memory.
你需要将这个输入放在哪里？这个输入来自这些设备，你需要将它们存储在内存中。
Right? Because why? Because your program, in order to operate to the input,
对吗？为什么呢？因为你的程序需要输入才能运行。
it has to find the input in memory because the program operates only on data in memory.
它必须在内存中找到输入，因为程序只能在内存中操作数据。
Right. And that's pretty much it. Now, this is one example, and this is an old example,
好的。基本上就是这样了。现在，这只是一个例子，而且是一个旧的例子。
many years back. And this is from Sun Enterprise. Again, Sun, it was a big company of workstations
很多年前。这是来自Sun Enterprise的。再次提到，Sun是一家工作站的大公司。
and it was acquired many years back by Oracle. But in the heyday, this was a great company.
而且它在多年前被Oracle收购了。但在鼎盛时期，这是一家伟大的公司。
And if you think about the devices and only looking in terms of the speed,
而且如果你考虑设备，并且只从速度的角度来看，
you have keyboards, like I mentioned, and the system bus, the system bus, it's learning the
你有键盘，就像我之前提到的一样，还有系统总线，系统总线，它正在学习。
system bus on the machine, which connects different devices, which are on the same enclosure on the
机器上的系统总线连接着同一机箱上的不同设备。
machine, like for instance, this storage and things like that. There are differences,
机器，例如，这个存储和诸如此类的东西。有一些区别，
it's two orders of magnitude. So you need to provide interfaces which can cope with such a huge
这是两个数量级的差距。因此，你需要提供能够应对如此巨大差距的接口。
variation in the speed. Okay.
速度的变化。好的。
So this means that, and you need to have something which works very well
所以这意味着，你需要有一些非常好用的东西。
when you have high throughput. So the overhead for transfer per byte should be very low. At the
当你有高吞吐量时，每字节的传输开销应该非常低。在这种情况下，传输的开销应该很小。
same time, if it's something very slow, you shouldn't just waste time waiting for the slow
同时，如果是一些非常缓慢的事情，你不应该浪费时间等待缓慢的进展。
devices. It's like if something happens one per second, you cannot wait once for the entire second
设备。就好像如果每秒发生一次事件，你不能等待整整一秒。
to get one character. Okay. This is another way to look about, and this is to put everything in
获得一个角色。好的。这是另一种思考方式，就是把一切都放在一起。
one picture about what we learned so far and what we are going to learn today. Right on the left
一张关于我们迄今所学和今天将要学习内容的图片。就在左边。
hand side, you have the processor and the processor obviously has the CPU, but in addition to CPU has
在右手边，你有处理器，而处理器显然有CPU，但除了CPU之外还有什么呢？
some storage, right? And the storage comes into registers, then a bunch of caches, L1 and L2 cache,
一些存储空间，对吗？然后存储空间进入寄存器，接着是一系列的缓存，L1和L2缓存。
which are the server core. And then you have an L3 cache and the L3 cache typically shared
哪些是服务器核心。然后你有一个L3缓存，L3缓存通常是共享的。
across multiple cores. And then you have memory and secondary storage and maybe another tertiary
跨多个核心。然后你还有内存、二级存储，也许还有另一个三级存储。
storage and so forth. And the difference between this kind of storage hierarchy, it's obviously
存储等等。以及这种存储层次结构的区别，显然是
like going from registers all the way from this to disk storage. You have at each level, it's much
像从寄存器一直到磁盘存储这样的过程。在每个层级上，它都有很多。
larger capacity, but also higher life latency. Right? So we learn about that. And we learn that
更大的容量，但也更高的寿命延迟。对吗？所以我们了解到这一点。而且我们了解到
about caching, we learned about demand paging and so forth. And in addition to that, here on the top
关于缓存，我们学到了需求分页等等。除此之外，在这里的顶部还有
with the yellow, you have all these devices, which again, needs to be available, the data which is
随着黄色，你拥有所有这些设备，再次需要可用的数据。
read from these devices to be available to processor. And then for the processor to write
从这些设备中读取的数据对处理器来说是可用的。然后处理器可以进行写入操作。
data to these devices, like to storage, to screen for you to see an image. And typically all these
数据传输到这些设备上，比如存储设备，屏幕上显示给你看图像。通常所有这些设备都可以完成这些功能。
devices are, they have a controller and this controller is what the name implies, controls
设备是有控制器的，这个控制器就如其名字所示，用来控制设备。
these devices because these devices are different. In some sense, this yellow box provides this
这些设备因为它们是不同的。从某种意义上说，这个黄色盒子提供了这个。
magical interface, which is reasonably uniform across all the devices to the processor and to
神奇的界面，在所有设备上都相对统一，对处理器和对其进行翻译。
the programmer. But in the back is doing this heavy lifting to uniformize these APIs by dealing
程序员。但在后台，正在进行这项繁重的工作，通过处理这些API来使其统一化。
with such a heterogeneous set of devices. Okay. So now let's look a little bit into more details
使用如此多样化的设备。好的。现在让我们稍微详细地看一下。
to see how things are on a computer. Right. And this is what you have on your computer. This is
要在电脑上看看情况。对的。这是你电脑上的东西。这是什么？
actually on your laptop or iPad. At some level, this is what you have. Okay. And you have processors,
实际上在你的笔记本电脑或iPad上。在某种程度上，这就是你所拥有的。好的。而且你有处理器，
obviously, and you may have other, you may have GPUs, you may have a network card here.
显然，你可能还有其他设备，你可能有GPU，你可能在这里有一张网络卡。
Of course, you have some storage devices, you may have big speakers, internal and external speakers,
当然，你可能有一些存储设备，你可能有大音箱，内置和外置音箱。
you may have a printer, of course, keyboards, you have the monitor, and many more. Right. So again,
你可能有一台打印机，当然，键盘你也有，还有显示器，还有很多其他设备。对吧。所以，再说一遍，
you need to take all this information from these devices to get into process, and then to write
你需要将这些设备上的所有信息提取出来，然后进行处理，最后进行写作。
back information at least to some devices, some of these devices, of course, you don't need to
将信息返回至至少一些设备，当然，并非所有设备都需要。
write back information to the keyboard, keyboard is only an input device. As a printer, it's only
将信息写回键盘，键盘只是一个输入设备。作为打印机，它只是一个输出设备。
an output device. And how do you connect them? Right. So first of all, how you wire them.
一个输出设备。你如何连接它们？对的。首先，你要如何连接它们。
So it turns out that the way you wire them is through this bus, you have a bus, right? So
原来，你将它们连接的方式是通过这个总线，你有一个总线，对吗？所以
everything goes to a bus, everything, including actually even the memory on the machine. And the
所有东西都被传送到了一辆公交车上，所有东西，包括实际上机器上的内存。而且
data is sent through this bus. Okay. And this is how you get the data into the processor. This is
数据通过这个总线发送。好的。这就是将数据输入处理器的方式。这是
how you get the data out of the processors through one bus. And more precisely, what is a bus?
如何通过一个总线从处理器中获取数据。更准确地说，什么是总线？
It represents the set of specifications. It specifies what are the wires, how many wires
它代表了一组规格。它指定了有多少根线，以及这些线是什么样的。
they have, it has, and how you connect to it. And then on top of that, it has to provide an API.
他们有，它有，以及你如何连接它。而且除此之外，它还必须提供一个API。
Read, write, how do you read and write from this bus? And you also have how you are going to
读、写，你是怎么从这辆公交车上读和写的？而且你还有你要怎么去的方式吗？
address a particular device. And for the particular device, you also have not only data reading,
地址一个特定的设备。而对于这个特定的设备，你不仅可以进行数据读取，
reading data, but you have also control data, right? Like for instance, for a disk, like you'll
读取数据，但你也有控制数据，对吗？比如说，对于一个磁盘，你会有控制数据吧？
see, you need to tell the disk where a particular block is on the disk to read or to write.
看，你需要告诉磁盘在磁盘上的特定块的位置，以便进行读取或写入。
This is happening through the control lines, right? And the controller, like you see the
这是通过控制线进行的，对吗？而控制器，就像你所看到的那样。
yellow box, is going to decide and instruct using the control line, a device, what to do,
黄色盒子将使用控制线来决定和指示一个设备该做什么。
and where to get the data from or to write the data to. And then there is also the protocol. You
还有数据的获取和写入位置。还有协议的问题。
have multiple devices which are going to send the data on the same bus. So what do you need to do?
有多个设备将要在同一总线上发送数据。那么你需要做什么？
Right? Not all of them can send the data at the same time, right? In general, you have only one
对吗？并不是所有的都能同时发送数据，对吗？一般来说，你只有一个。
device being able to send data on the bus at a given time. So this means that you need to
在给定的时间内能够在总线上发送数据的设备。这意味着你需要
arbitrate. If more than one device wants to send the data on the bus at the same time,
仲裁。如果有多个设备同时想要在总线上发送数据，
then you need to arbitrate who is going to be allowed to send and who is going to wait.
那么你需要仲裁谁可以发送，谁需要等待。
Okay. And of course, the devices here are, again, remember about they are very different in speed.
好的。当然，这里的设备，再次提醒一下，它们在速度上非常不同。
The devices which are close to the processor, like memory, things like that, they are very,
接近处理器的设备，比如内存，诸如此类的东西，它们非常重要。
very fast. The ones which are very remote, like are much slower, like say, you know,
非常快。那些非常偏远的地方，比如说，速度要慢得多，就像你知道的那样。
keyboard or printer. So now why a bus? This is very important. It may seem that this is obvious.
键盘或打印机。那么现在为什么是公交车呢？这非常重要。这可能看起来很明显。
Of course, it's a bus, right? But think about what is the alternative. So an obvious alternative here,
当然，这是一辆公交车，对吧？但是想想还有什么其他选择。所以在这里一个明显的替代方案是，
it will be to connect every device to the processor, right? And if the two devices have
是的，它将连接每个设备到处理器，对吗？如果这两个设备有
to communicate among themselves, you're also going to connect between them, right? The problem is that
为了让他们之间进行交流，你也会连接他们之间的联系，对吗？问题是
then you are going to have, in the worst case, you have n devices and you can have, you know,
然后在最坏的情况下，你会有n个设备，你可以有，你知道的。
n square connection. You don't want that. It's very complicated. Okay? So that's why what you
说的是n平方连接。你不想要那个。非常复杂。好吗？所以这就是为什么你
want, you have this bus and everyone is connected to the bus and then it's beautiful. Then you
想要的话，你可以拥有这辆巴士，每个人都与巴士连接在一起，然后就很美好了。然后你...
multiplex the bus in time. But the problem is that if you multiplex in time, then it may be
及时复用公交车。但问题是，如果你及时复用，那么可能会导致
very inefficient because remember all these devices have very, very different speeds.
非常低效，因为记住所有这些设备的速度都非常非常不同。
So, you know, like for instance, if I'm going the keyboard, right, it's like a key, right? You
所以，你知道的，比如说，如果我去键盘，对吧，就像一个键，对吧？
click a key and it takes a gain. It's like every one second. It's like, it's very inefficient way
点击一下键盘就会有收益。就像每一秒钟一样。就像，这是一种非常低效的方式。
of that bus, right? Because in the same time, you may send if, you know, from memory, you can send
那辆公交车的，对吗？因为在同一时间，你可以发送，如果你知道的话，从记忆中，你可以发送什么。
hundreds of gigabits per second, which means, you know, a few tens of gigabytes per second. Okay?
每秒数百千兆位，也就是说，你知道的，每秒几十千兆字节。好吗？
So it's very inefficient, right? You don't, you know, if you have slow devices,
所以这很低效，对吧？你知道的，如果你有慢速设备的话，
very inefficient for very fast devices. Okay. And so that's one of the big problems.
非常低效对于非常快速的设备。好的。这就是其中一个大问题。
Advantage against simplicity, everyone connects to it. The standard bus is today's,
优势在于简洁，每个人都可以连接到它。标准巴士是当今的选择。
is PCI is called Peripheral Component Interconnect. And it started as a parallel bus. Parallel bus,
PCI（Peripheral Component Interconnect）是一种并行总线。
meaning that at one device at a time is going to use to be able to send data and it can send data
这句话的意思是一次只能有一个设备能够发送数据，并且它能够发送数据。
in parallel. If he sends, you know, and the weights of the bus represents how many bits you can send
同时进行。如果他发送，你知道，而公交车的重量代表着你可以发送多少位。
in parallel. So for instance, if you have 128 bits, this means that you are going to be able to
同时进行。例如，如果你有128位，这意味着你将能够同时进行。
send in one clock cycle, 128 bits, right? And you multiply this, this, this bus like we discussed,
每个时钟周期发送128位，对吗？然后你将这个总线进行乘法运算，就像我们讨论过的那样。
but now the problem, if it's a slow device, then you are going to, you know, use, and also it
但现在的问题是，如果设备运行缓慢，那么你在使用时会感到很困扰，而且还有...
doesn't have, it sends only eight bits while the bus is 128 bits. You are going to waste on 20
没有，它只发送8位，而总线是128位。你将浪费掉20。
bits while this device is alone using the bus for sending just eight bits. Okay. So I'm going to,
在这个设备独自使用总线发送仅有八个位时，需要一些时间。好的。所以我要...
to stop here. Any questions about so far? Okay. So this is a little bit again, it's like very
停在这里。关于目前为止的任何问题吗？好的。所以这又是一点点，就像非常
descriptive, a lot of heterogeneity. So maybe a little bit boring, but it will, it will change.
描述性的，有很多的异质性。所以可能有点无聊，但它会改变的。
So now you may have heard about PCI express bus. So what is the problem is that it's parallel.
所以现在你可能听说过PCI Express总线。问题是它是并行的。
This is great. You know, it's simple, but only one device can use at the same time. And if it's
这很棒。你知道，它很简单，但一次只能使用一个设备。而且如果它被其他设备连接，你就不能使用它了。
a slow device, you waste so much time for the fast devices. So PCI express is pretty smart.
一个慢速设备，你为了快速设备浪费了太多时间。所以PCI Express相当聪明。
So it's no longer, no longer parallel bus. You still have multiple lines,
所以它不再是并行总线。你仍然有多条线路，
but they are serial channels. And you can, now a device can choose how many lines it's going to send.
但它们是串行通道。而且现在，设备可以选择发送多少行。
Do you use to send? Right? So for instance, if you have a very slow device, like your keyboard,
你是用来发送的吗？对吗？所以例如，如果你有一个非常慢的设备，比如你的键盘，
right, you can use to send everything on one line, right? And you leave all the other lines for
是的，你可以将所有内容都放在一行发送，对吗？而其他行你都留空就可以了。
others, like memory, right access to memory or the storage. Okay. So this allows the slow devices
其他的，比如内存，可以正确地访问内存或存储器。好的。所以这样可以让慢速设备
to share the PCI bus with fast devices in an efficient way. And again, the beauty of this,
以高效的方式与快速设备共享PCI总线。再次强调，这的美妙之处在于，
of Linux and Unix behind it, before it was that, you know, the ability to support all of these,
在它之前，是Linux和Unix的基础，你知道的，它有能力支持所有这些。
you know, not only to migrate from PCI to PCI express, but again, to provide a pretty uniform
你知道，不仅仅是从PCI迁移到PCI Express，而且还要提供一个相当统一的。
interface across all these devices. Okay. And also the API itself remains the same,
所有这些设备的接口都是一样的。好的。而且API本身也保持不变。
most pretty much the same. And this is quite amazing, right? If you think about it,
大部分都差不多。这真的很惊人，对吧？如果你仔细想想的话，
because Unix, when it was designed, Unix, I mean, a lot of
因为Unix在设计时，Unix，我是说，很多
things you have today, maybe they are not available then. You don't, you didn't have
你今天拥有的东西，也许那时候是没有的。你没有，你以前没有。
GPUs for instance. I'm sure you didn't have a lot of this kind of game, you know, game inputs,
例如，GPU。我相信你没有很多这种类型的游戏，你知道的，游戏输入，
devices, right? And many other things, right? So despite that, you started to connect things
设备，对吗？还有很多其他东西，对吗？所以尽管如此，你开始连接事物。
to the computer, which are not envisioned when people designed the operating system in the first
对于计算机来说，在人们最初设计操作系统时并没有设想到的东西
place. The operating system was still being able to preserve the same API. Of course, you need to
地方。操作系统仍然能够保持相同的API。当然，你需要
implement controllers or drivers, which are going to provide, you know, to support these devices
实现控制器或驱动程序，这些控制器或驱动程序将提供支持这些设备的功能。
and provide the same kind of abstraction like before, right? We'll talk more about that. Okay.
并且提供与之前相同的抽象层，对吗？我们会更详细地讨论这个问题。好的。
Anyway, here is an example of the PCI architecture. Today, you have a PCI number zero,
无论如何，这里是PCI架构的一个例子。今天，你有一个PCI编号为零，
PCI number zero here. And this is very fast one. This is connected to the CPU
PCI编号为零。而且这是一个非常快速的接口。它连接到CPU。
and the CPU is also having a memory bus to the RAM. Then there is a PCI bridge here.
而且CPU也有一个连接到RAM的内存总线。然后这里还有一个PCI桥接器。
You have another PCI bus. This PCI bus is a little...
你有另一个PCI总线。这个PCI总线有点...
bit typically slower. And this connects the storage devices, for instance, a scanner,
有点通常会慢一些。这个连接存储设备，比如扫描仪，
and all the webcam, mouse and keyboard. And then you have another bridge here from PCI
和所有的网络摄像头、鼠标和键盘。然后你还有一个来自PCI的桥接器。
to ESA. So ISI, it was an older bus standard. So you may still have devices, for instance,
向ESA（欧洲航天局）发送。所以ISI是一种较旧的总线标准。所以你可能仍然拥有设备，例如，
hard disk drives, which support, which implements this standard and connect to this ISI bus.
硬盘驱动器，支持并实现了这个标准，并连接到这个ISI总线。
And this is a bridge, so then you can use these devices on PCI architecture.
这是一座桥梁，所以你可以在PCI架构上使用这些设备。
So here, let's go into a little bit more detail. So how does a processor talk to all these
所以在这里，让我们更详细地讨论一下。那么处理器是如何与所有这些进行通信的呢？
devices? So here is a CPU and you have the memory and you have a memory bus here. And
设备？这里有一个CPU，你有内存，还有一个内存总线。而且
now you have, this is connected through a bus adapter to get data from this device controller.
现在你有了，这是通过总线适配器连接的，用于从这个设备控制器获取数据。
Right, remember, each device has a controller. And the device, you send the instructions
对的，记住，每个设备都有一个控制器。而且，你发送指令给设备。
about what data to get or to write. And the controller is talking with the device to get
关于获取或写入哪些数据。控制器正在与设备进行通信以获取数据。
what the program asks for. Now, within a device controller, a device controller is quite complicated.
程序要求什么。现在，在设备控制器内部，设备控制器非常复杂。
Actually many device controllers, they have their own processor. So it's like their own
实际上，许多设备控制器都有自己的处理器。所以就像它们有自己的
computer, right? They have ARM processor and so forth to implement the program, which is
计算机，对吗？它们使用ARM处理器等来执行程序。
going to control that device. Of course, we have a bus interface to send the data in and
要控制那个设备。当然，我们有一个总线接口来发送数据进去。
out to connect to the other buses in the system. And it has a memory, you can, for instance,
连接到系统中的其他公交车。它还有一个内存，例如，你可以
for doing, for caching data. For instance, when you send data to the printer, you can
用于执行，用于缓存数据。例如，当您将数据发送到打印机时，您可以
assume that it's not like you send one byte is printed, you send one byte is printed.
假设不是你发送一个字节就打印一次，而是你发送一个字节就打印一次。
No, you send a lot, almost the entire file, or you can send the entire file, which is
不，你发送了很多内容，几乎是整个文件，或者你可以发送整个文件，这是可以的。
kind of stored, that is part of it in local memory, and then it's printed from there.
部分存储在本地内存中，然后从那里打印出来。
And then this is very important. You have a set of registers here, which are, these
然后这一点非常重要。你这里有一组寄存器，它们是...（需要具体指明寄存器的名称或描述）
are the registers to which they are used to interact with this controller. They are used
这些寄存器用于与该控制器进行交互。它们被使用。
to tell the controller what to do, right? And, you know, read, write, or configure,
告诉控制器该做什么，对吗？而且，你知道，读取、写入或配置。
to configure the controller in a particular way. It's also to get the status of the controller.
将控制器配置为特定方式。还可以获取控制器的状态。
The status of the controller can be busy, right? The printer is busy, right? Showing
控制器的状态可以是忙碌的，对吗？打印机忙碌，对吗？显示中。
the status, not sorry, this is the status of the device controlled by the controller.
设备的状态，不是抱歉，这是由控制器控制的设备的状态。
Okay, another important thing, if you remember, we have this kind of interrupts, right? You
好的，另一个重要的事情，如果你还记得，我们有这种中断，对吧？
remember about the interrupts? And one of the main issues of interrupt is to react when
记得中断吗？中断的一个主要问题是在发生中断时做出反应。
something happens in the external world. And one of the main use cases there, it's about
外部世界发生了一些事情。其中一个主要的应用场景是关于什么？
when you have some data to get from a device, from the network, for instance, or when some
当你需要从设备或网络等地方获取一些数据时，比如说，或者当一些情况下
device needs attention, right? So that's what the interrupt controller and the controller
设备需要注意，对吗？所以这就是中断控制器和控制器的作用。
is going to raise some interrupts. And the interrupts are, if you remember, the operating
系统将会引发一些中断。而这些中断，如果你还记得的话，就是操作系统的
system, depending on the interrupt, is going to have an interrupt handler, which is going
系统根据中断的不同，会有相应的中断处理程序来处理。
to handle that interrupt, right? The network card has, and another controller has new data,
处理那个中断，对吗？网络卡有，另一个控制器有新数据。
is going to interrupt, to raise an interrupt, the OS is going to handle that interrupt,
将要中断，提出一个中断，操作系统将处理该中断。
and is going to read the data from the controller. Okay. Now, how do I interact? How do I program
并且将从控制器读取数据。好的。现在，我该如何进行交互？我该如何编程？
these controllers? There are two ways. Port mapped IO, in and out instructions. So basically
这些控制器？有两种方式。端口映射IO，输入和输出指令。所以基本上
here for the Intel architecture in particular, you have say out 0x21. So this is an address.
在这里特指Intel架构，你说的是0x21。所以这是一个地址。
This is an IO. So each IO has its own address. Each IO device has its own address. And basically
这是一个输入/输出设备。所以每个输入/输出设备都有自己的地址。每个输入/输出设备都有自己的地址。基本上，
out 0x21, AL means that the content of register AL is a register. So the content of that register
out 0x21, AL 意味着寄存器 AL 的内容是一个寄存器。因此，那个寄存器的内容
will be written on that output, at that address, to that output, will be written to that output.
将会被写入到那个输出，在那个地址，到那个输出，将会被写入到那个输出。
And you have the corresponding in and from a particular port address. And then the data
并且你有对应的进入和从特定端口地址发送的数据。然后是数据。
from that port is going to be written in register AL, for instance. Okay. So you have special
从那个端口将被写入到寄存器AL中，例如。好的。所以你有特殊的
instructions here, right? And special addresses for these devices. On the other hand, you
这里是说明吗？还有这些设备的特殊地址。另一方面，你
can have memory mapped IO. And this is pretty cool. You basically reserve your, you configure
可以进行内存映射IO。这非常酷。你基本上保留了你的，你进行配置。
some addresses in the memory, in the RAM. Okay. And this being are connected to these
一些内存中的地址，即RAM。好的。而这些地址与这些东西相连。
input output devices. Okay. And then the only thing you do, you use load and store, because
输入输出设备。好的。然后你唯一要做的就是使用加载和存储，因为
it's memory. Load means if I am going to put the data there at that particular address,
这是内存。Load的意思是，如果我要将数据放在特定的地址上，
that data is going to be sent to the corresponding device. Right? If I get, if I read the data
那些数据将会被发送到相应的设备。对吗？如果我理解正确的话，如果我读取这些数据。
from that, from a particular address, which is memory mapped address, then I'm going to
从那个特定的地址开始，这是一个内存映射地址，然后我要...
read data from the corresponding device. Make sense? This is an example about memory mapped,
从相应的设备读取数据。有意义吗？这是一个关于内存映射的示例。
right? And this is really used for graphics. Right? So typically, typically here, what
是吗？这个真的用于图形吗？对吗？那么通常，在这里通常是什么意思？
you have is that, you know, like your screen is a bitmap. Right? You know that, right?
你有的是，你知道，就像你的屏幕是位图一样。对吧？你知道的，对吧？
So the screen, the control of a screen, sees the same memory, you know, have a region,
所以屏幕，屏幕的控制，看到的是同样的内存，你知道的，有一个区域，
you devote a region of your RAM, you devote to that, to the screen. And when you are going,
你将你的一部分RAM分配给屏幕。当你使用时，你将其分配给屏幕。当你离开时，
and then you, when you are going to modify this memory, see how, what you modify, you
然后你，在你要修改这个记忆的时候，看看，你要修改什么，你要如何修改，你。
see immediately on the screen. Right? And so, so from here, display memory is from this
立即在屏幕上看到。对吗？所以，从这里开始，显示内存是从这里开始的。
address 800, whatever, 10,000 to 800, 8,000, whatever, F000, this is a display memory.
地址从800，不管是10000到800，不管是8000，不管是F000，这是一个显示内存。
In addition to that, you may have also a command queue, because you may have, you can provide
除此之外，你还可以有一个命令队列，因为你可能会有这个需求，你可以提供。
some commands to the display, you know, for instance, because you may have, like, higher
一些对显示器的指令，你知道的，比如，因为你可能有，像，更高的
level abstractions, rather than just writing and reading, writing individuals in the individual
层次抽象，而不仅仅是写和读，写个体在个体中。
bits, like, for instance, generating triangles, right, you are going to basically command,
位，比如说，生成三角形，对吧，你基本上要给出指令，
give a command to the controller, the controller, which is a graphic card is going to, to generate
给控制器发送一个指令，这个控制器是一个图形卡，它将要生成什么？
this kind of, say, triangles to create much faster, to render much faster, some, you know,
这种，比如说，三角形可以创建得更快，渲染得更快，一些，你知道的。
impressive, you know, objects. Okay. So this is, this is one thing. So again, that in summary
令人印象深刻，你知道，物体。好的。所以这是，这是一件事。所以总结一下，
from in summary here, in this is very simple example, you are going to have a region on
从这里总结起来，在这个非常简单的例子中，你将拥有一个区域。
the RAM, which is seen both by processor, and is seen by both and also by the controller,
内存，它既被处理器看到，也被控制器看到。
the video controller, right. And when you write, when the processor writes to this address,
视频控制器，对的。当处理器写入这个地址时，
to this memory, you see it on the screen. So, any questions? Now, it turns out that
对于这个记忆，你在屏幕上看到了它。那么，有什么问题吗？现在，结果是这样的，
today with this, everyone knows about GPUs, you know, graphical processing units, and
今天，大家都知道GPU，你知道的，图形处理单元，还有
the GPUs, they have actually their own memory. So you don't have the sharing. And the reason
显卡实际上有自己的内存。所以你没有共享的情况。而原因是什么呢？
for that, because the memory thing on the because the memory is a GPU, if the memory
对于这个问题，因为内存是一个GPU上的东西，如果内存
is on the GPU, that is much, much faster. So you can, you know, render much faster,
是在GPU上进行的，速度快得多。所以你可以，你知道的，渲染得更快，
much quicker. That's one of the reasons. This is for you to know. And of course, you can
更快。这是其中一个原因。这是让你知道的。当然，你也可以。
protect this memory regions using address translation like we know. Now, here is an
保护这些内存区域，使用我们所熟知的地址转换。现在，这里是一个
interesting thing. So far, we saw it, we told, I told you how it's, you know, that you have
有趣的事情。到目前为止，我们看到了它，我们说了，我告诉过你它是怎样的，你知道的，你有的。
this processor, and you have all these other storage devices and IO devices around it,
这个处理器，以及你周围的所有其他存储设备和IO设备，
and they are connected by the bus. But if a look in the processor into a processor itself,
并且它们通过总线连接在一起。但是，如果将目光投向处理器本身，
you see some similar things, because in a processor is not a monolith. In a processor,
你看到一些相似的东西，因为处理器并不是一个整体。在一个处理器中，
remember, you have multiple cores, you have multiple caches, and so forth. So how, and
记住，你有多个核心，你有多个缓存等等。那么如何，以及
actually many CPUs today, they also have graphic unit, right? Or neural unit, right, like some
实际上，如今许多CPU也具备图形单元，对吗？或者神经单元，对吗，就像一些
of the Apple chips have. Right? So, and then how do you connect those? Well, the answer
苹果芯片的优势是什么？然后，你如何将它们连接起来？嗯，答案是
is through a bus, right? Okay. So it's again, it's like what you see is outside, you know,
是通过公交车吗？好的。所以，就像你看到的是外面的景象，你知道的，
you know, outside the CPU, it's also pretty similar inside the CPU, you have different
你知道，在CPU之外，CPU内部也非常相似，你有不同的部件。
components, like here are a few examples, like I mentioned, and they are connected by
组件，比如这里有几个例子，就像我之前提到的一样，它们是通过连接的。
a bus. By the way, HDX is a software guard extension. So this is basically, it's a software,
一辆公交车。顺便说一下，HDX是一种软件保护扩展。所以基本上，它是一种软件。
it's a hardware enclave for people who, you know, for people who took a security course,
这是一个为那些参加过安全课程的人设计的硬件飞地。
a class. And yeah. And then you are going to have, then you are going to connect outside
一个班级。是的。然后你要有，然后你要连接到外部。
the CPU, you are going to connect to the memory, DDR, this is the memory. And you are going
将CPU连接到内存条，DDR，这是内存条。你需要
also, you see here, you are going to have a PCI Express, right? This is how you connect
还有，你看这里，你会有一个PCI Express，对吧？这是你连接的方式。
to the PCI Express to the rest of your devices. This is another way to look at, this is again,
将PCI Express连接到您的其他设备。这是另一种观点，再次强调，
Skylake system configuration. This is the same GPU here. It's pretty old, but today's
Skylake系统配置。这里使用的是同样的GPU。它相当老了，但在今天仍然可以使用。
on the ones today are not very different. Okay. And you have, you have here, basically,
今天的款式并没有太大的区别。好的。你这里有，基本上，
you know, you have, this is a core, and this is connected to memory. Then you have the
你知道，你有这个，这是一个核心，它连接到记忆。然后你有...
PCI Express, it's again to directly connect to other I/O devices. And then you have this
PCI Express 是一种直接连接其他输入/输出设备的接口。然后你还有这个...
bridge, and you have another chip which connects to other I/O devices. And this typically saves
桥接，你还有另一个芯片连接到其他输入/输出设备。这通常可以节省
a little bit slower devices in general, right? USB, audio, video, LAN, and so forth. So it's
一般来说，设备的速度会稍慢一些，对吧？USB、音频、视频、局域网等等。所以它的速度会稍慢一些。
again the same picture, emphasizing this pattern of multiple components being connected by
再次出现相同的图片，强调这种由多个组件连接而成的模式。
bus, fast buses. Okay, any questions? So now I mentioned to you that one of the
公交车，快速公交车。好的，有什么问题吗？所以现在我向你提到了其中一个
beauty and the successes of Unix and Linux, obviously, is that they were able to provide
美丽和Unix和Linux的成功显然在于它们能够提供
an API which remain pretty much the same over time, despite a proliferation of I/O devices.
一个API在时间推移中基本保持不变，尽管I/O设备不断增多。
And the reason for that is because obviously, they got abstraction, right, right. And they
因为显然，他们有抽象概念，对吧，对吧。而且他们
already recognize early on, there are different type of devices and they are going to handle
已经早早认识到，有不同类型的设备，它们将会处理。
with different with these devices slightly different. So how, how these devices are segmented?
这些设备之间有些微不同。那么，这些设备是如何分割的呢？
First is data granularity. When I'm going to read and write from a device, what is the
首先是数据粒度。当我要从设备中读取和写入数据时，这是什么意思？
granularity of the data I'm going to use? Lowest granularity is like byte, in some cases,
数据的粒度是什么？最低的粒度类似于字节，在某些情况下，
there is bit but it's rare, it's byte, right? You read one byte at a time, you write one
有一点点，但很少见，是字节对吗？你每次读取一个字节，写入一个字节。
byte at a time. But there are other devices, many other devices where you write at a higher
每次一个字节。但是还有其他设备，很多其他设备，你可以以更高的速度写入。
granularity, like a block, like to disk, or reading or writing from a disk, or reading
细粒度，像一个块，像写入磁盘或从磁盘读取，或者从磁盘读取。
or writing from the network. So it's it's, it's a level of granularity, it's a packet.
或者从网络中写入。所以它是一个粒度级别，它是一个数据包。
So now, let's make a little bit this class more interactive. Why do you think that? Why
所以现在，让我们稍微让这堂课更加互动一些。你为什么这么认为呢？为什么？
byte is not is not enough? Why not just have the ability to read and write only at the
字节不够用吗？为什么不只具备读写能力呢？
background? Anyone can tell me? It's exactly what's bad. Yeah. And actually,
背景？有人可以告诉我吗？到底是怎么回事。是的。实际上，
and this is correct. So if you write and read as a by granarity, then you need to this means
这是正确的。所以如果你将其作为一种粒度来写和阅读，那么你需要这样理解。
if you if you think about from the perspective, this is an API to the publication. And I want
如果你从这个角度考虑的话，这是一个用于出版的API。而且我想要
to read and write a byte, this translates to a system call, a system call, translate
读取和写入一个字节，这会转化为一个系统调用，一个系统调用，转化。
to a context switch. So the overhead, right, to read and write a byte is non trivial. Right?
对于上下文切换来说，读写一个字节的开销是不可忽视的，对吗？
You cannot sustain keep up with very fast IO devices. Okay. So that's the reason. So
你无法跟上非常快速的IO设备。好的。所以这就是原因。所以
byte is fine for keyboard, right? But it's not going to be fine for sending, you know,
字节对于键盘来说可以，对吗？但是对于发送来说就不行了，你知道的。
data to a gigabit per second. Because the fixed cost of send operation or receiving
数据传输速度为每秒一千兆比特。由于发送或接收操作的固定成本，
operation is too high. Okay. But they got it right from day one, because they have to
操作太高了。好的。但是他们从一开始就做得很对，因为他们必须这样做。
support the disk. Okay. And the disk couldn't do it efficiently at byte level. So they have
支持硬盘。好的。但是硬盘在字节级别上无法高效地完成这个任务。所以他们做了一些改进。
to have blocks. Okay, good. Access pattern, sequential versus random. You know, some devices
具有块。好的。访问模式，顺序与随机。你知道，有些设备
this must be accessed sequentially if you have a tape and others are randomly. Now,
这必须按顺序访问，如果你有一个磁带，而其他的是随机的。现在，
also there are devices which are under this access pattern beyond it's like, are you going
还有一些设备在这个访问模式之外，就像它一样，你要吗？
and we are going to talk more about that? Do you need to monitor that IO device all
我们要更多地讨论这个问题吗？你需要监控那个IO设备吗？
the time to see what happens or you are going to get interrupts when something happens?
你是想问，在某件事情发生时，是要等待看看会发生什么，还是会被打断吗？
Right? Like with a keyboard or a card. But now let me ask you again, it's like, for instance,
对吗？就像用键盘或卡片一样。但现在让我再问你一次，就像，例如，
about sequential versus random. Why not have only one? Forget about tape for now. Right?
关于顺序和随机的问题。为什么不只选择一个？暂时忘记磁带，对吗？
Remove tape, you know, because that with tape it's obvious, right? It's like, you know,
移除胶带，你知道的，因为有胶带的话很明显，对吧？就像，你知道的，
it's that, you know, it's, you have to access data on sequentially. But even without that,
这是这样的，你知道的，它是，你必须按顺序访问数据。但即使没有这个，
tell me, why not have random? Right? Because if I have random access pattern, then it doesn't
告诉我，为什么不能随机访问呢？对吧？因为如果我有随机访问模式，那就不行了。
make sense. I mean, I can emulate sequential, right? I start from one and then I say one,
有道理。我的意思是，我可以模拟顺序，对吗？我从一开始，然后我说一，
now I want to get two, three, four, five, six by three, two, three, four, five, six,
现在我想要用三、两、三、四、五、六来乘以二、三、四、五、六。
right? After all, in memory, I have only random access. I don't have sequential access. So
对吗？毕竟，在内存中，我只有随机访问。我没有顺序访问。所以
why sequential access? Why not random? Yes, Michael. Yeah, it's good. We'll learn. Because
为什么是顺序访问？为什么不是随机访问？是的，迈克尔。是的，很好。我们会学习的。因为
the random may involve some non-trivial overhead to locate that random piece of information.
随机可能涉及一些非平凡的开销来定位那个随机的信息片段。
That's why. Like we'll see with the disks. And therefore, if I'm going to store the bytes
那就是为什么。就像我们将在磁盘上看到的那样。因此，如果我要存储字节
and I can read or write them sequentially, it's going to be much, much faster. So you
而且如果我可以按顺序读取或写入它们，速度会快得多，非常非常快。所以你
see in both these cases, you can do, you can get away only have read/write as a level of
在这两种情况下，你可以做到的是，你只需要具备读写的能力就可以了。
byte and only accessing randomly. But you are going to leave a lot of performance on
字节和仅随机访问。但是你会浪费很多性能。
the table. So block and sequential, block randomization and sequential access pattern,
这是一个关于表格的话题。所谓块和顺序，是指块随机化和顺序访问模式。
one of the main reasons they are used is for performance reasons. Okay.
它们被使用的主要原因之一是出于性能考虑。好的。
Now the transfer mechanism, how is this?
现在转账机制，是怎样的呢？
Program I/O or DMA, Direct Memory Access.
程序输入/输出或DMA，直接内存访问。
Program I/O means the processor takes a byte from one device
程序的输入/输出意味着处理器从一个设备中取出一个字节。
and transfers to another device.
并且转移到另一个设备。
Like for instance, takes a block of data from the disk
例如，从磁盘中获取一块数据。
and put it in memory.
并将其存入内存中。
It's doing in, out, and low stuff.
这是在进行内部、外部和低层次的工作。
It's simple.
这很简单。
You can program everything through the computer.
你可以通过计算机编程任何东西。
The disadvantage is that you are going
缺点是你要去的话
to use a CPU for doing that.
使用CPU来完成这个任务。
You are going to consume these resources just moving
你只是在移动中消耗这些资源。
the data around, not doing useful work.
数据四处飘荡，没有做有用的工作。
The second way is Direct Memory Access.
第二种方式是直接内存访问（Direct Memory Access）。
And now this is a smart one.
现在这个是聪明的。
In this case, you say you are going to deal with two devices.
在这种情况下，你说你要处理两个设备。
And basically, you are going to tell one controller
基本上，你要告诉一个控制器。
from one device, well, you have to transfer the data directly
从一个设备到另一个设备，嗯，你需要直接传输数据。
to this other device.
发送到另一个设备。
This CPU is going to send instructions
这个CPU将发送指令。
how the transfer should happen.
转让应该如何进行。
But then the transfer happens between the devices
但是转移发生在设备之间。
without the CPU being involved.
不涉及CPU的情况下。
And here is an example.
这是一个例子。
And typically, this is one of the devices is typically
而通常，这是其中一个设备通常是什么。
memory.
记忆。
And here what happens?
这里发生了什么事情？
So you have a PCI bus and you have a memory.
所以你有一个PCI总线和一个内存。
And here you have a disk.
这是一张光盘。
And I want to transfer the data from the disk to the memory,
我想将数据从磁盘传输到内存。
to read the data from the disk into memory.
将数据从磁盘读入内存。
These are the steps.
这些是步骤。
The CPU number one.
CPU编号一。
The CPU is going to--
中央处理器即将--
the program starts to say, I want
程序开始说，我想要什么
to read the data from the disk.
读取磁盘上的数据。
Now, under the hood, the OS is going to handle that
现在，在底层，操作系统将处理这个。
and is going to send a message, control message,
并且打算发送一条消息，控制消息，
to the IDA disk, the controller disk controller telling it,
将IDA磁盘连接到控制器磁盘控制器，并告知它。
OK, you need to get this data to this address in the memory.
好的，你需要将这些数据传送到内存中的这个地址。
Address X. Now, the controller is going to tell this, OK,
地址是X。现在，控制器要告诉这个，好吗？
I need to--
我需要--
I was instructed to move this data,
我被指示移动这些数据。
to transfer this data to memory, to this address X.
将这些数据传输到内存，到地址X。
And now the DMA is doing the rest.
现在DMA正在处理剩下的事情。
The DMA, not the CPU, is going to handle the transfer
DMA将处理传输，而不是CPU。
from the disk controller to the memory.
从磁盘控制器到内存。
So the DMA is going to read the data from the ID
所以DMA将从ID中读取数据。
and then drive the data on the CPU bus to the memory.
然后将数据驱动到内存中的CPU总线上。
Once the transfer is completed, the DMA
一旦转移完成，DMA
is going to send an interrupt to the CPU telling,
将向CPU发送中断信号，告知
I am ready.
我准备好了。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Pretty cool, right?
相当酷，对吧？
So when do I/O devices are notifying the operating system?
I/O设备何时通知操作系统？
Right?
对吗？
Two reasons.
两个原因。
When it was-- well, the OS--
当它是--嗯，操作系统--
think about from the OS perspective,
从操作系统的角度来思考，
what do you need to know?
你需要知道什么？
On the other hand, you need to know if you are instructed,
另一方面，你需要知道是否有指示。
you have instructed a controller,
你已经指示了一个控制器。
I/O controller to perform some operation.
I/O控制器执行某些操作。
You want to know when that operation is completed.
你想知道那个操作何时完成。
The second is if there is an error.
第二种情况是如果出现错误。
Right?
对吗？
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So and like you mentioned, one way to handle that
所以，就像你提到的那样，处理这个问题的一种方法是
is I/O interrupt.
是输入/输出中断。
Whenever there is one of these events
每当发生这些事件之一时
that OS needs to know about, the I/O controller
那个操作系统需要知道的是输入/输出控制器。
raises an interrupt.
引发中断。
OK.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
Why this is good?
为什么这个好？
The CPU doesn't need to worry about.
CPU不需要担心。
I'm going-- the CPU is going to--
我要走了——CPU要——
the device-- the I/O controller is going to let the CPU know
这个设备--输入/输出控制器将会让CPU知道。
and something worse knowing happens.
发生了一些更糟糕的事情。
But also, you can handle unpredictable events
但是，你也可以处理不可预测的事件。
like a new packet arriving on the network.
像一个新的数据包到达网络一样。
The disadvantage is that the interrupts are expensive.
缺点是中断的成本较高。
It's a context switch.
这是一个上下文切换。
You know, when the CPU--
你知道，当CPU--
when I raise an interrupt, maybe most likely a process,
当我触发一个中断时，很可能是一个进程。
a user process was executed.
一个用户进程被执行了。
So you need to do a context switch
所以你需要进行上下文切换
to go through the operating system, handle the interrupt,
通过操作系统来处理中断。
and then to go back in the user mode
然后返回到用户模式。
to continue running the process.
继续运行该进程。
The other one is polling.
另一个是投票。
So this is operating system periodically check
所以这是操作系统定期检查。
a device specific status to see whether it's ready.
一个设备特定的状态，用于查看它是否准备就绪。
Remember that I showed you in the I/O controller,
记得我在输入/输出控制器中向你展示过，
one of these registers was called status.
其中一个寄存器被称为状态。
So for instance, it's going to be a printer.
所以例如，它将是一台打印机。
I was always--
我一直都是--
I want to know when the printer is done,
我想知道打印机什么时候完成。
when the printing is done.
当打印完成时。
So I can tell the user, OK, the printer is done.
所以我可以告诉用户，好的，打印机已经完成了。
Whatever you send to the printer is done.
无论你发送什么给打印机，都已完成。
So in that case, the controller has this status register,
那么在这种情况下，控制器有这个状态寄存器。
and it's going to be updated when
并且它将在更新时进行更新。
the printer is no longer busy when
打印机不再忙碌时。
the file finished being printed.
文件已经打印完成。
And then the OS is periodically going to check on that.
然后操作系统会定期检查这个。
And when it's no longer busy, it's
而当它不再忙碌时，它就是
going to turn to the application.
准备转向应用程序。
Now the pro here is low overhead because the OS
现在这里的优势是开销低，因为操作系统
is going to check on this between contact switches.
将在接触开关之间进行检查。
It doesn't need to do a contact switch to just to check.
它不需要进行联系开关，只是为了检查。
This one, the operating system gets--
这个，操作系统得到--
the kernel gets control.
内核获得控制。
It's also going to check this.
这也要检查一下。
Now the con is that you check and nothing happens,
现在的问题是你检查了，但什么都没有发生，
then that's wasted time, CPU cycles.
那么这就是浪费的时间和CPU周期。
OK?
好的。
So now, typically you combine those.
所以现在，通常你会将它们结合起来。
There is no right solution.
没有正确的解决方案。
That's why you have to do both of them.
这就是为什么你必须两者兼顾。
If you do only one solution, why would
如果你只做一种解决方案，为什么会这样呢？
have I told you about both?
我有告诉过你两个都吗？
But let me take a step back now and ask you,
但是现在让我退后一步，问问你，
when are you going to use IO interrupts?
你打算什么时候使用IO中断？
And there is a little bit of an answer here.
这里有一点点答案。
But I just want you to give the answer in your own words.
但是我只希望你用你自己的话来回答。
When do you think you should use IO interrupts?
你认为什么时候应该使用IO中断？
When do you think you should use polling?
你认为什么时候应该使用轮询？
Give me another-- this is one example
给我另一个——这是一个例子。
you have here on the slide.
你在这张幻灯片上有什么。
Give me another example.
给我另一个例子。
[AUDIO OUT]
[音频关闭]
Let me ask you, keyboard, right?
让我问你，键盘，对吗？
Are you going to use polling or interrupts?
你打算使用轮询还是中断？
Human IO for interrupts.
人机交互用于中断。
OK, that's good.
好的，没问题。
Why is that?
为什么这样呢？
Why human IO for interrupts?
为什么人类IO用于中断？
Rare and slow and--
稀有而缓慢的——
you see here?
你看到这里了吗？
Oh, sorry.
哦，抱歉。
Unpredictable, right?
不可预测的，对吧？
It's unpredictable.
这是不可预测的。
If it's something unpredictable, it
如果是一些不可预测的事情，那就
doesn't make sense to poll forever, right,
不断进行投票没有意义，对吧？
for something rare to happen.
为了某件罕见的事情发生。
Yes, Gilbert.
是的，Gilbert。
So your interrupt for frequent sinks,
所以你打断了频繁的沉思，
polling for stuff we need to continuously check.
持续检查我们需要的东西。
Yes, or if something happens--
是的，或者如果发生了什么事情--
yeah, this for polling, someone, you
是的，这是用于投票的，有人，你。
say this for polling, sometimes actually you don't use.
说这个是为了进行投票，有时候实际上你并不使用。
We'll see.
我们会看的。
But it's not necessary that you are going to poll the disk.
但并不一定需要你去轮询磁盘。
Yeah.
是的。
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So yeah, for the keyboard, eventually it's again,
所以，对于键盘来说，最终又是这样，
you have to use the interrupt because this
你必须使用中断，因为这样
is to tell the operating system when some keyboard is pressed.
是用来告诉操作系统某个键盘被按下的。
Because if you watch a movie for two hours
因为如果你连续观看电影两个小时的话
or whatever on your computer, you don't type anything, right?
或者你的电脑上有其他什么东西，你不需要输入任何内容，对吗？
Or zoom, like right now.
或者现在就用Zoom。
You are listening to this lecture, right?
你在听这个讲座，对吗？
I hope that you are not doing a lot of many things other
希望你没有做很多其他的事情。
than listening to the lecture.
比听讲座更好。
But still, right, it's like if you are listening,
但是，对吧，就好像你在倾听一样，
you don't touch it.
你不要碰它。
You don't have the keyboard.
你没有键盘。
So it's very rare event.
所以这是一个非常罕见的事件。
Doesn't make a lot of sense to poll.
不太有意义进行投票。
One of the things, the reason you poll
你询问的原因之一是什么？
is like in this example, when things
就像在这个例子中一样，当事情...
happens extremely frequent, right?
发生得非常频繁，对吗？
Once you get, for instance, a packet here,
一旦你在这里收到一个包裹，
you get so many other packets one after another.
你接连收到了这么多其他的包裹。
You cannot afford to have a context switching per packet.
你不能承受每个数据包的上下文切换。
When the context switching is--
当上下文切换发生时--
the overhead of context switching
上下文切换的开销
is larger than the time between the events,
比事件之间的时间更长，
it probably doesn't-- it's not worth the context switching.
它可能不会——这样做并不值得切换上下文。
It's not worth the interrupts, right?
这不值得打断，对吗？
Let me put it in another way.
让我换个方式来表达。
So say context switching gets one millisecond
所以说，上下文切换需要1毫秒。
and picking some random number, right?
然后选择一些随机数，对吗？
And then say an event happens every 10 microseconds.
然后说每隔10微秒就会发生一个事件。
It makes no sense to do the interrupts for event, right?
对于事件来说，做中断没有意义，对吗？
You just poll to see for that.
你只是进行调查而已。
OK, very good.
好的，非常好。
So this is a structure in the kernel for the device.
这是内核中用于设备的一个结构。
So you have the system call interface.
所以你有系统调用接口。
We'll talk more about them.
我们会更多地谈论他们。
And you have some for memory--
你还有一些关于记忆的东西--
this is what we learned for all.
这是我们为所有人学到的东西。
We have process management, memory management,
我们有进程管理、内存管理、
file systems.
文件系统。
And then you have the device control.
然后你有设备控制。
This is for I/O devices and then networking.
这是用于输入/输出设备，然后是网络。
Networking typically is different in apps.
网络通信在应用程序中通常是不同的。
So the API also for networking is slightly different.
所以网络方面的API也略有不同。
OK, so the device control--
好的，所以设备控制--
what is-- when we say--
什么是--当我们说--
so the device control--
所以设备控制--
the control for the device, this is typically implemented
设备的控制，通常是通过实现来完成的。
on the device itself.
在设备本身上。
But this device now has to also interface with the operating
但是现在这个设备还必须与操作系统进行接口。
system.
系统。
The piece of software which--
这个软件的一部分--
the piece of software which bridges the operating system
这个软件是用来连接操作系统的。
API with the controller API is called device driver.
使用控制器API调用的API被称为设备驱动程序。
And it's a piece of code which runs in the operating
而这是一段在操作系统中运行的代码。
system, in the kernel.
系统，在内核中。
And it is the piece of code.
这是一段代码。
It implements the Unix I/O API.
它实现了Unix的I/O API。
What is that API?
那是什么API？
Well, this is the thing which survived so many decades.
这就是那个经历了这么多年的东西。
Remember, open, close in order to communicate to a device.
记住，打开，关闭以便与设备进行通信。
You open, you close.
你打开，你关闭。
Then read and write.
然后阅读和写作。
And you can read as a program or you can read as a program.
你可以将其理解为一个节目，也可以将其理解为一个计划。
And IO-CTL, IO control, this is a escape patch.
IO-CTL，IO控制，这是一个逃避补丁。
Because each device can have--
因为每个设备都可以有--
is a little bit different, requires a little bit
有一点不同，需要一点点。
different configurations.
不同的配置。
This is what is IO-CTL is.
这是IO-CTL是什么。
It's more for device specific control.
这更多是用于设备特定的控制。
Now, the device driver is two halves.
现在，设备驱动程序分为两个部分。
One, which basically is executed in the user mode,
一，基本上是在用户模式下执行的。
and the other one which is executed in the kernel.
另一个是在内核中执行的。
Sorry.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
Both top and half--
两者皆为顶部和一半--
bottom and half of the device drivers
设备驱动程序的底部一半
are executed in the kernel.
在内核中执行。
The top one, it provides--
最上面的那个，它提供--
it helps to provide the kernel IO API, which
它有助于提供内核IO API，该API可以
is used by the user program to interact with these devices.
被用户程序用来与这些设备进行交互。
So let's see what happens.
那么让我们看看会发生什么。
So let's say you have a user program
那么假设你有一个用户程序。
and request an IO operation, say, to write data to the disk.
并请求进行IO操作，比如说，将数据写入磁盘。
First of all, is that--
首先，那是什么？
is the request already satisfied or something like that?
请求已经满足了吗，或者类似的情况？
It's like this happens when this happens.
就像这样，当发生这种情况时会发生这种情况。
This happens, for instance, if I am going
这种情况发生在我要去的时候，例如。
to read some data from the disk.
从磁盘中读取一些数据。
And when I read the data from the disk,
当我从磁盘上读取数据时，
the granularity at which the data is transferred from the disk
数据从磁盘传输的粒度
is larger than what I read.
比我读的要大。
Say, I read only 10 bytes.
说，我只读了10个字节。
But when I'm going to transfer from the disk,
但是当我要从磁盘上转移时，
I'm going to transfer one page is four kilobytes.
我将传输一页，大小为四千字节。
So these four kilobytes is already stored in memory.
所以这四千字节已经存储在内存中了。
So now, I am just going to--
所以现在，我只是要--
if I read those first 10 bytes, then I
如果我读取那前10个字节，那么我
can read the next 10 bytes.
可以读取接下来的10个字节。
They're already in memory.
它们已经在内存中了。
So I don't need to do invoke to touch the device again.
所以我不需要再次触摸设备来执行操作。
But let's say now it's not satisfied.
但是现在假设它不满意。
So now, I'm going to send the request to the device.
所以现在，我要将请求发送到设备。
And well, send the request to the device driver.
好的，将请求发送给设备驱动程序。
The device driver is looking at the request.
设备驱动程序正在查看请求。
And from here on, this code, it's device specific.
从这里开始，这段代码是特定于设备的。
I process the request.
我处理这个请求。
And then you send it to the device hardware.
然后你将它发送到设备硬件。
So this is the device driver.
这是设备驱动程序。
This is on the hardware.
这是关于硬件的事情。
So this part, it's on the kernel.
这部分是关于内核的。
In the kernel, this part at the bottom
在内核中，这部分位于底部。
can be in the device driver.
可以在设备驱动程序中实现。
It can be in the device itself.
它可以在设备本身中。
And the device, the controller, is
而这个设备，控制器，是什么？
going to execute the operation.
准备执行该操作。
Say, for instance, instruct the disk
说，例如，指示磁盘。
where to read the data from.
从哪里读取数据？
Then read the data.
然后阅读数据。
Once it reads the data, it buffers.
一旦读取数据，它会进行缓冲。
It sends an interrupt.
它发送一个中断信号。
Sorry.
对不起。
And the interrupt is sent to the kernel.
中断被发送到内核。
The kernel is going to handle this interrupt.
内核将处理这个中断。
It's going to get the data from the device.
它将从设备中获取数据。
And then it's going to see whether the I/O is completed.
然后它会检查I/O是否完成。
And if it's completed, it's going to let the application
而且如果完成了，它将允许应用程序
know.
知道。
OK.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you need to be translated.
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So the goal of the I/O subsystem-- so I/O,
I/O subsystem的目标是处理输入/输出（I/O）操作，
it's, again, to provide this interface uniform interface.
这是为了提供一个统一的界面。
And so that uniform interface means--
所以这个统一的接口意味着--
so uniform API means that the code
统一的API意味着代码可以在不同的平台和系统上运行。
you wrote for one particular device
你写的是针对特定设备的。
should work potentially with very minimal changes
应该可以在非常小的改动下潜在地工作。
for other devices.
适用于其他设备。
So for instance, for this code, this switch opens some code
所以例如，对于这段代码，这个开关打开了一些代码。
and then prints some output.
然后打印一些输出。
It works on multiple devices.
它可以在多个设备上使用。
It works on this terminal.
它在这个终端上可以工作。
If FD is a terminal, the file descriptor is a terminal.
如果FD是一个终端，那么文件描述符就是一个终端。
It works for the disk if file descriptor is a file.
如果文件描述符是一个文件，它适用于磁盘。
And it can also work on the printer.
它也可以在打印机上使用。
The same code.
相同的代码。
OK.
Sure. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So now let's talk a little bit more about this interface
那么现在让我们再多谈谈这个界面。
and why the interface, again, has been
而为什么界面，再次，已经被修改了呢？
so powerful and so general.
如此强大且如此通用。
Like I mentioned to you, you have block devices.
就像我之前跟你提到的一样，你有块设备。
You have block devices.
你有块设备。
And for these block devices, you write the data,
对于这些块设备，你可以写入数据，
the block reality.
这是一个需要翻译的内容，我将其翻译为英文：the block reality.
And you have an open read, write, and seek, right?
你有读、写和查找的权限，对吗？
Then you can have character devices.
然后你可以拥有字符设备。
And this is the level you read and write the data
这是你读写数据的水平。
at the level of a single character.
在一个字符的层面上。
And for this, you have also open read.
而且为此，你也打开了阅读。
But you have also for getting a single character,
但是你也可以获取一个单个字符，
you get a get input API.
你可以使用一个获取输入的API。
And then for network devices, this
然后对于网络设备，这个
is different enough that you have a different API,
不同到足以需要一个不同的API，
slightly different API.
略有不同的API。
You still have open and close, but you
你仍然有开和关，但是你
have the concept of sockets.
有套接字的概念。
And you still have reads and writes, read, write,
你仍然有读和写的权限，读取，写入。
and open and close.
打开和关闭。
All of them are still--
他们都还是--
you still have those.
你还有那些东西。
But in addition, you have other richer API.
但是除此之外，你还有其他更丰富的API。
If you remember, you have connect, you have accept.
如果你记得的话，你已经连接了，你已经接受了。
You have also something else, which is select.
你还有其他的东西，那就是选择。
Select is when you are going to listen on connection
选择是当你打算监听连接时使用的。
from multiple computers.
从多台计算机。
You are going to learn more about that.
你将会了解更多关于那个的信息。
But these are the three standard interfaces provided
但是这些是提供的三个标准接口。
by the operating system.
由操作系统控制。
And each of the devices falls in one of these categories.
每个设备都属于这些类别之一。
Block device.
块设备。
a character device or a network device.
一个字符设备或网络设备。
Next,
接下来，
how you are going with respect to timing,
你在时间方面进展如何？
how do you interact with the devices?
你是如何与设备进行交互的？
Well, there are a few ways to interact.
嗯，有几种互动的方式。
One is a blocking interface.
一个是阻塞接口。
The blocking interface,
阻塞接口
when you are going to perform an operation,
当你准备进行一项手术时，
you are going to wait for that operation to finish.
你将等待那个操作完成。
Right?
对吗？
When you request, say for instance,
当你请求时，比如说，
when you read some data,
当你阅读一些数据时，
you are blocking until the data you requested is available.
你将一直阻塞，直到你请求的数据可用。
Then it's non-blocking interface.
那么它就是非阻塞接口。
You don't, you know, you just write some data
你不需要知道，你只需要写一些数据。
and the call returns immediately before the data is written.
并且在数据写入之前立即返回呼叫。
Okay?
好的。
Now,
现在，
so this is obviously you don't know the result,
所以显然你不知道结果。
but then you don't block.
但是你不会阻止。
So you are very efficient.
是的，你非常高效。
You don't write cycles on the CPU.
你不在CPU上写循环。
And then it's a synchronous interface.
然后它是一个同步接口。
And then this basically says,
然后这基本上是说，
I am going to request the data.
我将要请求数据。
And by the way,
顺便说一下，
here what you need to do,
这是你需要做的事情，
and let me know when you are done.
并且在你完成后告诉我。
So I wanted to read the data and you need,
所以我想读取数据，你需要的话，
so read the data from this device.
所以从这个设备中读取数据。
And I'm telling you that you need to put the data
我告诉你，你需要把数据放进去。
after this address in memory.
在这个内存地址之后。
Okay?
好的。
And you put that in the address in memory and tell me,
然后你将其放入内存中的地址，并告诉我，
you tell me when you are done with it.
你告诉我什么时候完成。
This is a synchronous interface.
这是一个同步接口。
Okay?
好的。
So some announcements,
一些公告，
unfortunately, you know,
很不幸，你知道的，
next week will be quite a week for you.
下周对你来说将是相当忙碌的一周。
So the good thing is that after the next,
所以好的一点是，在接下来的事情之后，
the following week, after the next week,
下周之后的那一周。
it's going to be easier.
这会更容易。
And the Thanksgiving is coming soon.
感恩节即将到来。
But yeah, next week will be hard.
但是，是的，下周会很辛苦。
You have a homework for midterm too.
你也有期中考的作业。
The review will be,
评论将会是...
how all will be on Monday.
星期一会怎样。
The time we are going to let you know the time.
我们将告诉您时间的时间。
The midterm will be on Wednesday
期中考试将在星期三举行。
between seven, nine p.m. Pacific time.
在太平洋时间晚上七点到九点之间。
As a project is due on,
截止日期快到了，
at the end of the next week and tomorrow,
下周末和明天的最后。
unfortunately yesterday, I had, like I mentioned,
不幸的是，昨天我有，就像我之前提到的那样，
a flight which was canceled and then rescheduled.
一次被取消然后重新安排的航班。
Between 11, 13 and 12, 13, I'll have my office hour.
在11点到13点和12点到13点之间，我会有办公时间。
Okay, let's move a little bit.
好的，让我们稍微移动一下。
We have another 15 minutes.
我们还有15分钟。
So let's move quick now.
那么现在让我们快点行动吧。
Storage devices.
存储设备。
So storage devices are where we store the data
存储设备是我们存储数据的地方。
and persistently, right?
而且是持续不断地，对吗？
They typically have much larger capacities than memory,
它们通常比内存具有更大的容量，
but they are slower, right?
但是它们更慢，对吗？
And we have magnetic disk and flash memories, right?
对的，我们有磁盘和闪存记忆。
There are two types.
有两种类型。
Magnetic disks are, you know,
磁盘是，你知道的，
these are traditional ones, flash memories are newer,
这些是传统的，闪存是较新的。
but now are dominant.
但现在占主导地位。
They are more expensive.
它们更贵。
They have provide better performance.
他们提供了更好的性能。
That's kind of the way to look at them.
这是一种看待它们的方式。
These are some examples.
这些是一些例子。
This is the disk drive, right?
这是磁盘驱动器，对吗？
You see here a platter.
你在这里看到一个盘子。
You have here the heads.
你这里有头颅。
We read and write the data.
我们读取并写入数据。
And then you are going to have,
然后你将会有，
here is another hard drive.
这里是另一个硬盘。
This is the heads.
这是头部。
You have multiple platters on each drive the data,
每个驱动器上都有多个盘片来存储数据。
and therefore you have heads on each platter,
所以你们每个盘子上都有头。
for each platter.
每个盘子。
And here it's a micro drive, this is this, right?
这是一个微型驱动器，对吗？
Now, just to give you a sense,
现在，只是为了让你有个概念，
the first IBM personal computer, which was released in 1986.
第一台IBM个人电脑于1986年发布。
So that was 35 years ago, right?
那是35年前的事情，对吗？
It has, the hard disk was $500.
它有一个硬盘，价格是500美元。
It was 30 megabytes, not gigabytes, megabytes.
它是30兆字节，不是千兆字节，是兆字节。
The seek time is how long it takes a random access.
寻道时间是指随机访问所需的时间。
It's those 30 to locate, you know,
这是那些30个要找的，你知道的。
to write the data randomly, or read the data randomly,
随机写入数据，或者随机读取数据。
or between 30 and 40 milliseconds.
或者在30到40毫秒之间。
And the speed, the maximum speed of transferring the data,
以及传输数据的最大速度，
what was one megabyte per second, okay?
一兆字节每秒是多少，好吗？
So how it looks like, this is how hard drive it looks like.
这是它的外观，这就是硬盘的样子。
You have the platters, the platter has two surfaces,
你有盘子，盘子有两个表面。
the up and down surface.
上下表面。
So you can write on both of them.
所以你可以在两个上面写。
On each of them, you are going to have tracks,
在每一个上面，你都会有轨道，
and the tracks are divided in sectors.
并且轨道被分成了扇区。
So the sectors stores a block.
所以这个部门存储一个块。
And this is a unit of storing, reading,
这是一个存储、读取的单位。
and writing data from the disk.
并从磁盘中写入数据。
And that is written, reads and writes
这是写的，读和写
are performed by the header, okay?
由标题执行，好吗？
So let's now show this one by one.
那么现在让我们逐一展示。
This is a sector, okay?
这是一个行业，好吗？
So you have this ring of sectors.
所以你有一个扇区的环。
This is a stack.
这是一个堆栈。
And then the corresponding tracks
然后是相应的曲目。
on all platters represent a cylinder.
所有的盘子都代表一个圆柱体。
What is important about cylinder?
圆柱体的重要性在于它的形状和特性。圆柱体具有平面底面和侧面，底面和侧面都是圆形的。它的特点是体积大且稳定，可以用来存储和容纳各种物体和液体。圆柱体在工程、建筑和科学领域中广泛应用，例如管道、柱子、容器等。此外，圆柱体还具有优秀的力学性能，能够承受压力和重量，因此在许多结构和机械设备中起着重要作用。
Is that the data from a cylinder can be written
是的，可以将数据写入圆柱体。
and read without moving the heads.
并且在不移动头部的情况下阅读。
Because the movement of heads,
由于头部的运动，
which is called SICK operation, is expensive, right?
这个叫做SICK手术的，很贵，对吗？
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
So some numbers, the disk track,
一些数字，磁盘轨道，
the tracks are around one micron wide.
这些轨道大约有一微米宽。
And this is very small.
这个非常小。
The wavelength of light, it's only half a micron.
光的波长只有半微米。
The resolution of human eyes is 50 microns.
人眼的分辨率为50微米。
So you have typically 100,000 tracks on a 2.5 inch disk.
所以你通常在一个2.5英寸的磁盘上有10万个轨道。
And you have these tracks in general,
而且你通常都有这些曲目。
separated by some guard regions,
分隔开一些警卫区域，
because you don't want right on a track
因为你不想在正确的轨道上。
to influence the bits on the others
影响其他人的想法
and corrupt, therefore, the bits on the nearby tracks.
并且腐蚀了附近轨道上的位。
Now, the tracks length varies, right?
是的，赛道的长度是不同的，对吗？
The one which are closer to the edges
靠近边缘的那一个
are larger than the one at the center.
比中心的那个大。
And so typically, we are only using half of the radius,
因此，通常情况下，我们只使用半径的一半。
only the tracks at the edges of that,
只有边缘的轨道。
because you have more space to store information.
因为你有更多的空间来存储信息。
If you store it too close to the center,
如果你将其存放得太靠近中心，
the sector is too small.
这个行业太小了。
You are going to get a lot of errors.
你会遇到很多错误。
And this card, obviously huge right now,
这张卡片，显然现在非常火。
there are terabytes in terms of capacity.
容量方面有几个泰字节。
So in general, only a small part of this data,
总的来说，只有这些数据的一小部分，
which is stored on the disk is active, redrived.
磁盘上存储的是活动的，重新驱动的。
The rest is used for being archived.
其余的用于存档。
And this is important.
这很重要。
Before, in the early days, you archive the data
之前，在早期，你会归档数据。
not on the disk, because it is quite expensive.
不在磁盘上，因为它非常昂贵。
You archive the data on magnetic tapes.
你将数据存档在磁带上。
One note, this is more like a footnote.
一点说明，这更像是一个脚注。
There is something which is called
有一样东西叫做什么？
single magnetic recording.
单磁记录。
And in this case, instead of having a guard
而在这种情况下，不是有一个守卫
between the tracks, you remember that I told you
在这些曲目之间，你还记得我告诉过你
that between tracks, you have the guards.
在轨道之间，你有护栏。
So you avoid writing, when you write on a track a bit
所以当你在一条轨道上写作时，你避免写得太多。
to influence the nearby tracks, right?
影响附近的轨道，对吗？
But in order in the race to add more and more bits,
但是为了在竞争中不断增加更多的位数，
to increase the capacity of the disks,
增加磁盘容量，
people came up with this technique,
人们提出了这种技术。
which actually in some sense,
在某种意义上，实际上是这样的，
the tracks kind of almost overlap.
这些轨道几乎是重叠的。
And obviously now you need to be very careful
显然现在你需要非常小心。
and need to have much more complex,
并且需要更加复杂的，
digital signal processing techniques
数字信号处理技术
in order to make sure that you avoid a bit being corrupted
为了确保你避免一点被损坏
by writing a bit in a nearby track.
通过在附近的轨道上写一点东西。
So, magnetic disk,
磁盘
it's again, you have the heads, cylinders, sectors,
这是再次出现的问题，你有磁头、柱面和扇区。
and tracks, and now let's see what is the time
和轨道，现在让我们看看现在是几点钟。
to read or write data, okay?
读取或写入数据，可以吗？
So first of all, this is how
首先，这是如何做的。
the architecture looks like.
这个建筑看起来像什么？
So the disk actually has a controller, right?
所以这个硬盘实际上有一个控制器，对吗？
Like we mentioned many times before.
就像我们之前多次提到的那样。
And you are going to get a request, right?
是的，我会收到一个请求，对吗？
The controller gets a request, right?
控制器会收到一个请求，对吗？
And let me just show you where this request is coming from.
让我给你展示一下这个请求的来源。
It's here.
它在这里。
You see the request, this is the request.
你看到了这个请求，这就是请求。
Okay?
好的？
And here we are talking about this device hardware.
我们现在正在讨论这个设备的硬件。
(silence)
对不起，我无法翻译空白的内容。请提供需要翻译的具体文本。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you need to be translated.
So you get the request, and then you have a queue
所以你收到请求后，就会有一个队列。
because multiple application can request data
因为多个应用程序可以请求数据。
to read and write data from the same time.
同时读写数据。
So you need to queue this request, right?
所以你需要将这个请求排队，对吗？
And then you have the hardware controller,
然后你还有硬件控制器，
which is going to take requests from this queue,
哪一个将会从这个队列中接收请求，
and that's going to satisfy the request.
这将满足请求。
Now, a request, when you satisfy the request, what happens?
现在
You need to figure out and assume that you already know
你需要弄清楚并假设你已经知道了。
where the data you need to read and to,
你需要读取和处理的数据在哪里？
where the data is located, right?
数据存储在哪里，对吗？
And in order to, once you do that, you need to move that,
而为了实现这一点，一旦你做到了，你需要移动那个。
you need to, so you need to identify
你需要这样做，所以你需要确定。
what you need to identify.
你需要识别什么。
You need to identify a sector.
你需要确定一个行业。
A sector means to identify the track, right?
部门是指识别轨道的意思，对吗？
In order to get to a track, you need to move the disk,
为了进入一首音轨，你需要移动光盘。
to move the heads.
移动头部。
The overhead to move the disk is called seek time.
磁盘移动的开销被称为寻道时间。
Then once you are above the corresponding track,
然后一旦你在相应的轨道上方，
you need to wait for the proper sector
你需要等待适当的部门。
to come under the head so you can read and write.
为了能够阅读和写作，你需要掌握一些基本知识。
This is the rotation time.
这是旋转时间。
And finally, the transfer time,
最后，转机时间是多久？
the time to read and write the information from the sector.
读取和写入扇区中的信息所需的时间。
Here are some numbers from some other magnetic disks.
这里是一些其他磁盘的数字。
It's a space like 14 terabytes.
这是一个像14TB一样的空间。
It's pretty eight platters.
这是相当不错的八个盘子。
Typically the seek time is four to six milliseconds.
通常的寻找时间为四到六毫秒。
This rotation, like rotation speed,
这个旋转，就像旋转速度一样，
the rotation per minute is like between 3,600 and 7,200.
每分钟的转速大约在3,600到7,200之间。
There are also some of the new, you know,
还有一些新的，你知道的，
faster disk at even 1,500 rotation per minute.
每分钟转速高达1,500转的更快磁盘。
Average latency of,
平均延迟为，
rotation latency is between four and eight milliseconds.
旋转延迟在四到八毫秒之间。
Right?
对吗？
This is, you know,
这个，你知道的，
if it takes eight milliseconds for a full rotation,
如果一次完整的旋转需要八毫秒的时间，
then on average, you need to wait for four milliseconds
然后平均而言，你需要等待四毫秒。
rotation latency in order for the sector
旋转延迟以便扇区
you are looking for to come under the disk,
你想要放在盘子下面，
under the head.
在头部下方。
And transfer time between 50 and 250 megabytes per second.
并且传输速度在50到250兆字节每秒之间。
The transfer sector is typically between
转让行业通常介于两个部门之间。
512 and one kilobyte and things like that.
512和一千字节之类的东西。
Right?
对吗？
They used to drop,
他们过去常常下降，
the cost used to drop by a factor of two every 1.5 years.
成本曾经以每1.5年减少一倍的速度下降。
It's no longer true.
不再是真的了。
So now let's go through this example.
那么现在让我们来看一下这个例子。
So assuming that we ignore the queuing
所以假设我们忽略排队的情况
and the controller times.
和控制器的时间。
Okay?
好的？
So we ignore this queuing time and the controller time.
所以我们忽略这个排队时间和控制器时间。
Let's look only on the media time.
让我们只关注媒体时间。
Assume the average seek time is five milliseconds.
假设平均寻道时间为五毫秒。
Assume that the rotation, you know,
假设旋转，你知道的。
speed it's 7,200 rotation per minute.
速度是每分钟7200转。
So this means that it takes eight milliseconds
这意味着它需要八毫秒。
for a full rotation.
一整个旋转。
And the transfer rate assume is 50 megabytes.
并且假设传输速率为50兆字节。
Oh, so then the, sorry.
哦，那么，抱歉。
This is the transfer rate of 15 megabytes per second.
这是每秒传输15兆字节的速率。
If it's a block size of four kilobytes, right?
如果块大小是四千字节，对吗？
So assuming the transfer rate is 50 megabytes per second.
所以假设传输速率为每秒50兆字节。
If the block size is four kilobytes,
如果块大小为四千字节，
then it takes 0.8 milliseconds to transfer one sector.
然后传输一个扇区需要0.8毫秒。
Right?
对吗？
You divide four kilobytes, the size of a sector,
你将四千字节（一个扇区的大小）除以。
on the transfer rate, right?
关于传输速率，对吗？
To get that by.
把那个拿过来。
So then reading the block from a random place on the disk,
那么，从磁盘上的任意位置读取块，
you need to seek first to the track.
你需要首先寻找轨迹。
You need to wait for the sector and then you read it.
你需要等待扇区，然后再读取它。
So it takes nine milliseconds,
所以需要九毫秒。
a little bit more than nine milliseconds.
略微超过九毫秒。
Is equivalent to 450 kilobytes per second speed,
相当于每秒450千字节的速度。
you know, transfer speed.
你知道，传输速度。
If you read the block from a random place
如果你从一个随机的位置开始阅读这个区块
in the same cylinder, then if you do that,
在同一个汽缸中，如果你这样做的话，
you don't need to incur the seek time.
你不需要承担寻找时间的成本。
So now the latency is only 4.08 milliseconds,
所以现在延迟只有4.08毫秒。
which means that the data now rate
这意味着数据现在的速率是多少？
is one megabyte per second.
每秒钟是一兆字节。
But now assume that you just need the same,
但是现在假设你只需要相同的东西，
next sector on the track.
赛道上的下一个区域。
You sequentially read.
你是一个顺序阅读的人。
Then you don't need to incur the rotation delay either.
那么你也不需要承担旋转延迟。
So it's 50 megabytes per second.
所以每秒是50兆字节。
So it's 50 times bigger or 100 times bigger
所以它是50倍大还是100倍大？
if it's purely random.
如果这是纯粹的随机的话。
So now you see why you have seek.
所以现在你明白为什么你需要寻求了。
Also you have sequential access
你还可以顺序访问
and versus only random access, right?
对，这只是随机访问而已，对吗？
If you can sequentially access the data,
如果你可以按顺序访问数据，
it's so much faster, at least for the disk.
这样会快得多，至少对于磁盘来说。
So the key to use a disk effectively
使用磁盘的关键是
is to make sure that you, as much as possible,
是为了尽可能确保你，
you access the data sequentially, okay?
你按顺序访问数据，好吗？
So now there is a lot of intelligence
所以现在有很多智能。
in this embedded into this controller.
在这个嵌入到这个控制器中。
So the sectors, for instance,
因此，例如，这些行业，
you have sophisticated error correcting codes, right?
你有复杂的纠错码，对吗？
Because, you know, to avoid data corruption.
因为，你知道的，为了避免数据损坏。
And this is very important
这非常重要。
because if you store the data on a disk
因为如果你将数据存储在磁盘上
and you trust that disk because it's stored persistently.
你相信那个磁盘，因为它被持久地存储着。
So if the data is corrupted, you know, you lost the data.
所以如果数据损坏了，你知道的，你就丢失了数据。
Sector sparing.
扇区保留。
So it's again, it's like,
所以又是这样，就像是，
sometimes some sectors becomes bad.
有时候一些行业变得不好。
You can no longer read and write data reliably from them.
你无法再可靠地从它们中读取和写入数据了。
So in that case, you remap them.
那么在这种情况下，你需要重新映射它们。
You forget about those and you remap that
你忘记了那些，你重新规划了那个。
to transfer it to another spare sector on the disk.
将其转移到磁盘上的另一个备用扇区。
And this is done by the controller
这是由控制器完成的。
transparently with the software.
透明地使用软件。
Sleep sparing.
节约睡眠时间。
Now, if there is a bunch,
现在，如果有一堆的话，
if the sector goes bad,
如果这个行业走下坡路，
now the problem is that, you know,
现在问题是，你知道的，
now you no longer have sequential access.
现在你不再具有顺序访问的能力。
If you want to preserve sequential access,
如果你想保留顺序访问，
you may want to remap multiple sectors
你可能想要重新映射多个扇区。
to preserve the sequentiality.
保持顺序性。
And the last is track skewing.
最后一个是轨道偏斜。
And here I have a figure for you as a mean track skewing.
这里有一个数字给你，表示平均轨道偏斜。
So this means that if I want,
这意味着如果我想的话，
if the data is stored sequentially on nearby tracks,
如果数据按顺序存储在相邻的磁道上，
then I want to make sure that when I move
那么我想要确保当我搬家的时候
from one track to another, I don't waste time.
从一条轨道到另一条，我不浪费时间。
So here, you know, these are the sectors on track one.
所以在这里，你知道，这些是第一轨道上的部门。
So say I'm going to read on track one here, the head,
所以说我要在这里读第一轨，头部，
you know, I'm just finishing reading everything
你知道，我刚刚读完了所有的内容。
on the track one and I want to move to track two.
在第一轨道上，我想要切换到第二轨道。
The track two is the one inside.
轨道二是里面的那个。
Now, when I want to move,
现在，当我想要搬家的时候，
then the first sector on track one, I'm going to shift.
那么，我要将第一扇区移到第一磁道上。
So then this time,
那么这一次，
when I'm going to move the head to track one,
当我要移动头部来跟踪第一个的时候，
by the time I moved, now sector zero comes,
当我搬家的时候，现在是零区的时候了。
is ready to be read.
已准备好阅读。
If I don't do this, then while I move this head
如果我不这样做，那么当我移动这个头的时候
from one sector, from one track to another,
从一个行业到另一个行业，从一个轨道到另一个轨道，
I miss a sector zero and I need to wait
我想念一个零扇区，我需要等待。
for an entire evolution of the disk
整个磁盘的演化过程
before I start reading it, right?
在我开始阅读之前，对吗？
So, and I'm going to end up with this slide.
所以，我最后会得到这张幻灯片。
So this is an example of current hard disk drive.
这是一个当前硬盘驱动器的例子。
It's like 20, 20, 18 terabytes is a hard drive,
就像20、20、18 TB是一个硬盘一样。
nine platters, 18 hertz.
九个盘子，18赫兹。
Each platter has two sides.
每个盘子有两面。
So one head for each side.
所以每边一个头。
Four milliseconds, every six time.
四毫秒，每六次。
A sector is four kilobytes, 7,200 RPM and so forth.
一个扇区是四千字节，每分钟转速为7,200转等等。
And 270 megabytes per second maximum transfer rate
每秒最大传输速率为270兆字节。
costs 562.
费用为562。
Now let's compare with IBM personal computer drive,
现在让我们与IBM个人电脑驱动器进行比较，
the first drive.
第一次驾驶。
This was 86, okay?
这是86年的，好吗？
So the seek time is 10 times better, okay?
所以寻找时间好了10倍，对吗？
The transfer time is 300 times better.
转移时间提高了300倍。
But the capacity is 600,000 times better.
但是容量提高了600,000倍。
And the cost, it's almost the same, 600,000 times better.
而且成本几乎相同，好了600,000倍。
So this is a progress we were able to get in 36 years.
这是我们在36年内取得的进展。
Okay, so it's quite impressive.
好的，这真的很令人印象深刻。
Okay, so we are going to stop here
好的，所以我们要停在这里。
and next time we are going to start talking
下次我们打算开始交谈。
with about solid SSDs.
关于固态硬盘的事情。
Thanks everyone, okay.
谢谢大家，好的。
Okay, I'm going to stop here
好的，我就到这里。
and I'm going to answer the questions.
我会回答这些问题。
(silence)
对不起，我无法翻译空白的内容。请提供需要翻译的具体文本。
对不起，我无法翻译空白。请提供需要翻译的具体内容。
(silence)
对不起，我无法翻译空白的内容。请提供需要翻译的具体文本。
对不起，我无法翻译空白。请提供需要翻译的具体内容。
(silence)
对不起，我无法翻译空白的内容。请提供需要翻译的具体内容。
对不起，我无法翻译沉默。请提供需要翻译的具体内容。
.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
you
你